Guide to the Stanford Women's Club Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford Women's Club records
1910-1973
SC0491
Stanford Women's Club.
1.5 Linear feet (3 boxes)
The records include minutes, bylaws, financial records, correspondence, articles on Clubhouse history, and miscellaneous programs and clippings.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The Stanford Women's Club was incorporated in 1910 by a group of Stanford alumnae to continue earlier efforts on the part of students and faculty toward establishing a women's building on campus. The partially completed building, known as the Women's Clubhouse, was opened in February 1915. In 1966, the Women's Club deeded the Clubhouse over to the University. Since then, the Women's Club has concentrated on sponsoring a scholarship.
Description of the Collection
The records include minutes, bylaws, financial records, correspondence, articles on Clubhouse history, and miscellaneous programs and clippings. Volume two of the minutebooks includes a letter from Bertha Berner, Jane Stanford's personal secretary, concerning her gift of a portrait of Jane and Leland Stanford, 1944. Also of note is a journal kept during the construction of the Clubhouse, 1913-1914, with short entries on weather and the type of work being done.
Access Terms
Berner, Bertha.; Stanford Women's Club.; Women--California.; Women--Societies and clubs
Collection Contents
- Records, 1910-1973
  - Bylaws, 1910-1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutebook, 1910-1929 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutebook, 1929-1948 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Loan papers, 1915-1928 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Accounts, 1908-1915 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Accounts, 1915-1917 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Accounts, 1918-1920 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Accounts, 1920-1926 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Accounts, 1927-1929 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Accounts with Monson Brothers, disputed, 1915-1917 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Articles and talks pertaining to the Club and Clubhouse (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Clubhouse construction diary, 1913-1914 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Clubhouse, summary of total costs, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1948-1952 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Fundraising appeals, 1910-1935 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous programs, etc., 1914-1973 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Account book, 1915-1933 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Treasurer's Book, Volume II, 1933-1957 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Financial Operations, Volume III, 1956 Sep-1966 Aug 31 (Box 3, Folder 3)